Contact

+966567626056 (Mobile) sohaib.elsayad1@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sohaibelsayyad-b36873b0 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

ArcMap ArcGIS Pro Autodesk Civil 3D

Languages

English (Professional Working)

Arabic (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Getting Started with ArcGIS Pro Getting Started with Spatial Analysis Using GIS to Solve Problems Applying the Racial Equity Workflow Using ArcGIS

Getting Started with Mapping and Visualization

Sohaib Elsayyad

GIS Specialist & Professional Land Surveyor

Jeddah, Makkah, Saudi Arabia

Summary

Experienced Surveyor and Gis Specialist with a demonstrated history of working in the civil engineering industry. Skilled in AutoCAD Civil 3D , ArcGis Program , English, Microsoft Excel, and Microsoft Word. Strong real estate professional with a Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) focused in Surveying Engineering , Gis and Division of Maps from Mansoura University.

Experience

Al Sabq Al Arabi Traiding & Contracting 2 years 1 month

Geographic Information System Specialist August 2021 - January 2023 (1 year 6 months) Jeddah, Makkah, Saudi Arabia

(Eisal Project --Implementation of water house and sewerage connections. - Makah District- Jeddah city)

Supervision and follow-up of works to implement more than 1,200 domestic water connections all over the city of Jeddah:

- Conducting a field survey with the representative of the National Water Company for clients.
- Making and closing the permits on the Jeddah Municipality system.
- Closing transactions on the National Water Company (EAM) system.
- Organizing work sites and sending sites, photos and permits for transactions to work teams to facilitate and complete work.
- Surveying works for the executed works with GPS.
- Prepare reports for the company and the National Water Company.
- Creating the GIS data for the project.

(Contract No. (18A) --Implementation of house sewerage connections. -Al-Basateen District (1)- Jeddah city)

- Making and closing the permits on the Jeddah Municipality system.
- Surveying works for the executed works with GPS.
- Creating the GIS data for the project.

Professional Land Surveyor January 2021 - July 2021 (7 months)

At Taif, Makkah, Saudi Arabia

(Contract No. (7) --Completion of the sewage networks project for ALQAM - Ibn Rayhan in AL

Hulaqa and Al Rahmaniyah. -At Taif city)

- Surveyed terrain, prepared accurate schematic sketches, and reviewed collected data.
- Planned, monitored, and coordinated ground surveys; operated and maintained map reading equipment and tools.
- Record the results of surveys, including the shape, contour, location, elevation, and dimensions of land or land features.
- Coordinate findings with the work of engineering and architectural personnel, clients, and others.
- Establish fixed points for use in making maps, using geodetic and engineering instruments.
- Analyze survey objectives and specifications in order to prepare survey proposals or to direct others in survey proposal preparation.

Engineering Company for Integrated Projects ECIP Land Surveyor 2018 - 2020 (2 years)

Cairo, Egypt

(Chipsy Phase 3 Project in Alabour)

- Analyzed previous maps, physical evidence, and other documents.
- Experience using a total station to collect land survey data.

Cairo Consulting Company Land Surveyor 2017 - 2018 (1 year) Cairo, Egypt

(Transport links for the House of Al Watan project in Al-Rehab)

Ice food (Gersey Ice Cream) 6 years

Accountant 2012 - 2016 (4 years) El Mansoura, Ad Daqahliyah, Egypt

(Trade and distribution of ice cream products)

- Inputting and updating new information about accounts and customers into the user database.
- Compiled and sorted source data for submitting by computer.
- Checked for deficiencies in records for customers and accounts by processing customer data.

Data Entry Specialist 2010 - 2012 (2 years)

El Mansoura, Ad Daqahliyah, Egypt

(Trade and distribution of ice cream products)

- Inputting and updating new information about accounts and customers into the user database.
- Compiled and sorted source data for submitting by computer.

Education

Mansoura University

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Geographic Information system and Surveying Engineering. (2010 - 2014)